Guide to the Catherine Dickey Autograph Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Catherine Dickey autograph collection
1756-1973
MS 1760
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(4 boxes)
The collection, compiled by Catherine Colt Dickey (Mrs. Charles D. Dickey), includes autographs of United States presidents, signers of the Declaration of Independence, government officials, military figures, industrialists, educators, explorers, authors, and other well known persons in public life. Autographs appear on various mediums: letters; postcards; photographs; handwritten and printed documents; and small blank cards specifically designed to solely capture signatures.
Dickey, Catherine
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Custodial History
Gift of S. Whitney Dickey, 1999.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two parts: Unbound material and bound material. The unbound material is arranged alphabetically by writer's last name. Bound material is listed alphabetically by the cover title of each volume, with contents described in the order in which they were bound.
Scope and Contents
The collection, compiled by Catherine Colt Dickey (Mrs. Charles D. Dickey), includes autographs of United States presidents, signers of the Declaration of Independence, government officials, military figures, industrialists, educators, explorers, authors, and other well known persons in public life. Autographs appear on various mediums: letters; postcards; photographs; handwritten and printed documents; and small blank cards specifically designed to solely capture signatures.
United States -- Politics and government; Autographs (manuscripts); Dickey, Catherine
- Autographs, unbound
  Arrangement
  Autographs are listed alphabetically be correspondent's name.
  Scope and Contents
  The majority of the signed correspondence to Catherine Dickey consists of correspondents sending social pleasantries, such as thank you messages and arrangements to meet, whereas the correspondence to persons other than Dickey is often of a more substantive nature. Ephemera kept by Dickey is listed at the end of the inventory of unbound material.
  - To Catherine Dickey and/or Charles D. Dickey
    - Acheson, Dean and Alice, 1956 March 6, 29, 1960 January 8, 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Roy Chapman, 1941 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Letter by Andrews, director of the American Museum of Natural History, forwarded to Catherine Dickey regarding Robert (Bob) Bartlett and the Greenland Expedition. Included is the signature of Bob Bartlett on an autograph card, 1938 April 23.
    - Berry, Martha, autograph only, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Martha Berry was the founder of Berry College, Georgia, in 1902.
    - Boves, Kate, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1963 October 30, 1972 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Casey, Rick (Richard), 1967 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Drury, S. S., 1931 January 3, 24 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      S. S. Drury was the rector of St. Stephen's Church, Boston.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1958 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Elizabeth, Princess, 1947 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ford, Henry, II, 1972 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - French, Daniel C., 1929 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Gaines, Emma, autograph only, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      A former slave, Gaines was a leader in numerous educational and social organizations for the advancement of women.
    - Gates, Thomas S., Sr., 1956 December 7, 1957 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1959 December 7, 1961 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Lindsay, John, 1969 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Marshall, G. C., 1949 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - McGovern, George D., 1970 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Mercier, Cardinal, Archbishop of Malines, 1920 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Pendar, Kenneth, 1943 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Letter to Catherine Dickey includes correspondence of Mark W. Clark to Kenneth Pendar.
    - Pershing, John J., 1929 February 14, 1930 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes a letter of introduction for Pershing from unidentified correspondent.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
      A gravure photograph of Roosevelt inscribed to Mrs. Charles Dickey.
    - Sherrill, Henry K., Reverend, 1964 May 17, 1970 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Illegible signature on Commonwealth of Australia letterhead, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - To persons other than Catherine Dickey
    - Benjamin, _____, to Mrs. Sellar, 1882 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Booth, Edwin, autograph only, 1885 April (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bryan, George, to Thomas Bradford, Jr., 1820 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      George Bryan was a delegate to the Stamp Act Congress.
    - Cambreleng, Stephen to Aaron Dayton, 1829 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Carroll, Charles (of Carrollton) to Robert Barry, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chester, John, to Joseph Webb, 1776 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      John Chester, a graduate of Yale College in 1766, was a distinguished war hero during the Revolutionary War.
    - Clark, N. (?) Goodale, 1796 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Copyright document for Edmund March Blunt's book, "The (American) Coasting Pilot, " the first book of American sailing directions published in the United States.
    - Dahlgrew, John A., Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Autograph card with sketch of Rear Admiral Dahlgrew.
    - Dixon, William Hepworth, to unidentified recipient, No year, October 24 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Dixon, a prolific author, was the editor of Athenaeum and the author of New America.
    - Ellary, _____, invoice, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ellery, William, invoice for "horse keeping in public stables", 1780 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Ellery was a member of the Continental Congress and signer of the Declaration of Independence.
    - Ford, Henry, to Mrs. Sellar, No year, June 16 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd, to William Rathbone, autograph only, 1852 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Graham, John, to unidentified recipient, 1811 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Graham was chief clerk of the State Department (1807-1817).
    - Herford, Oliver, signed program for his play Epilogue, 1915 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hunter, W., to B. Perry, 1881 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Letter re General Asboth of Missouri.
    - La Fayette to [your excellency], 1781 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Detailed letter re La Fayette's military efforts to aid the United States against British invasions in the spring of 1781.
    - Mason, John, to General John Steele, 1813 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Letter regarding the petition of Captain Nathaniel Brewer for a cartel.
    - Popham (?), Anne, to unidentified recipient, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Porter, Darien (?) D., autograph only, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Porter, J., to William Jones, 1827 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Letter of recommendation for Joseph Pipe for the Office of Inspector.
    - Powell, J. H., to Mrs. Sellar, 1884 December 30 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Rantoul, R. (Robert), Jr., to Collector of Customs, Philadelphia, 1884 May (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Letter that accompanied list of crew of the Brig Antares.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1920 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Typed letter signed as Assistant Secretary of the Navy, Washington, to Edward Corning, New York, expressing appreciation that "you have made this early start in the great campaign...".
    - Sargent, Winthrop, to D. Appleton Company, request for books, 1842 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Sears, Joshua, brief note and clipping of obituary, 1833 April 20, 1857 February (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Silvester, ______, to John Smith, invoice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Wellington, Duke of, Circa 1915 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Wickliffe, Robert, to unidentified recipient, 1836 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Wilde, Oscar, to Grosvenor Gallery Library, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Winters, Elisha,to General Wayn(e), 1796 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified, illegible, 1848, 1861, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Ephemera, miscellany, unbound
    Handwritten notes are presumably by Catherine Dickey.
    - Handwritten notes regarding opening day, presumably of a London naval conference, 1930 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Handwritten notes regarding the signers of the Declaration of Independence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Handwritten notes regarding World War I, Circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Newspaper clipping from The New York Times regarding the sale of autograph letters and documents, 1971 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Newspaper clipping, "Argonne Echoes," by Edward S. Van Zile, Circa 1929 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Ships and sailing, 1814, 1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
      Includes facsimile of an invitation to a naval ball; handdrawn sketch of a ship; and newspaper article on "sea-going" yachts.
- Autographs, bound
  Volumes are listed alphabetically by the cover title; contents listed as bound. Loose materials found in some albums were added to the list of unbound materials.
  - "Autographs --Mrs. Charles D. Dickey --1920"
    The majority of signed correspondence in the two volumes is between individuals other than Dickey. Only a small number of items are addressed to Dickey family members.
    - Volume I, 1865-1949 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Volume II, 1622-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Autographs of the American, British, French, Japanese and Belgian Delegates to the Disarmament Conference Assembled at the Request Of President Warren G. Harding in Washington November 11th (Armistice Day) 1921" (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Autographs of the Presidents of the United States 1789-1925"
    The first autograph is that of Samuel Francis Smith, patriotic song writer; the remainder are presidential autographs.
    - Smith, Samuel Francis, 1894 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Handwritten lyrics of "America," aka "My Country 'Tis of Thee."
    - Washington, George, 1779 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Letter signed, folio, Head Quarters, Middle Brook [New Jersey], to Thomas Burke, delegate to the Continental Congress from North Carolina, relating to the sending of troops to the southern states.
    - Adams, John, 1784 October 4 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed (with integral address leaf), Auteuil, to Charles William Frederic Dumas at The Hague regarding the "Dutch Nation" and wishing success in forming a "Solid Coalition".
    - Jefferson, Thomas, 1792 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed (with integral address leaf), Philadelphia, to Mr. Church, United States Consul at Lisbon confirming Church's appointment.
    - Madison, James, 1803 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph note signed to an unnamed recipient expressing regret that the writer's query arrived too late to consult the necessary persons.
    - Monroe, James, 1815 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Washington, to Thomas Swan congratulating him on his appointment as a commissioner to settle the Yazoo claims.
    - Adams, John Quincy, 1845 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Washington, to William Whiting of Roxbury, Massachusetts, regarding Congressional action on pensions.
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1827 February 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Hermitage, to Mrs. Miriam Ayres concerning his attention to business and court records which she asked him to investigate on her behalf.
    - Van Buren, Martin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, oblong, no place, to his brother regarding a real estate transaction.
    - Harrison, William Henry, 1812 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Head Quarters, Franklin, to John H. Pratt regarding the securing of supplies and drivers.
    - Tyler, John, 1843 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed to Mr. Webster enclosing some letters relating to the Princess Metternich and others which he wants returned.
    - Polk, James K., 1845 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, as President, Washington, to Secretary of the Treasury Robert J. Walker asking Walker to see "an old lady who will hand you this note" and who is "in great distress".
    - Taylor, Zachary, 1825 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Louisville, Kentucky, to Colonel R. Jones discussing methods of securing recruits.
    - Fillmore, Millard, 1854 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed (marked private), Buffalo, to ...Pruyn? declining an invitation to attend the opening of a railway to Brantford and an evening ball.
    - Pierce, Franklin, 1856 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed as President, Washington, with autograph envelope, to Postmaster General James Campbell introducing Judge T. O. Wilson of Dubuque, Iowa, who has helpful information on the mails.
    - Buchanan, James, 1860 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph note signed, as President (with wax seal), Washington, to John I McConn? sending his autograph for the writer's son.
    - Lincoln, Abraham, 1864 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      A clemency order signed, as President, Executive Mansion, Washington, to Major General George G. Meade, Army of the Potomac, to suspend the execution of Benjamin Van Horn, of First Pennsylvania Artillery until further orders.
    - Johnson, Andrew, 1865 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Grant of Clemency signed, as President (with seal), folio, for Samuel Tate of Shelby County, Tennessee, who has voluntarily taken an oath of allegiance to the United States.
    - Grant, Ulysses S., 1884 December 16 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed to L. P. Hubbard, secretary of the New England Society of the City of New York expressing regrets that he cannot attend the Society's annual dinner.
    - Hayes, Rutherford B., 1891 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Spiegel Grove, Fremont, Ohio, with autograph envelope, to J. L. Hillard, clerk of Committees, City of Boston, expressing regret that he cannot attend memorial service honoring General Sherman.
    - Garfield, James A., 1880 July 29 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Mentor, Ohio, to Honorable Wirt Sikes of Cardiff, Wales, thanking him for sending "English Goblins".
    - Arthur, Chester A., 1883 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Letter signed (LS), as President, Executive Mansion, Washington, to William B. Brokaw thanking him for the presentation of the Newburgh Centennial Medal. Autograph signature on engraved White House card.
    - Cleveland, Grover, 1904 June 25 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Princeton, to J. B. Gilder, New York, discussing the return of proofs with maps and book dedication.
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1881 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, to Senate Chamber, Washington, to Honorable Warren G. Sayre, State Senate, Indianapolis relating to Harrison's Senate activities.
    - McKinley, William, 1878 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, House of Representatives, Washington, to T. C. Prince, Canton, Ohio, introducing Price to Captain Wills of the Naval Academy library.
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, No year May 12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, Sagamore Hill, Oyster Bay [New York] to "Dear Sir" indicating that he will be out of town for the summer.
    - Taft, William Howard, 1928 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed, on Supreme Court stationery, Canada, to Abraham Kunkel regarding the size and hanging of a picture.
    - Wilson, Woodrow, 1895 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed to Mr. Williams regarding a meeting in Philadelphia, with a steel-engraved portrait of Wilson signed in pencil.
    - Harding, Warren G., [1914] July 31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph letter signed oblong, to McMillan & Kayne regarding an order for cards. Broken at fold.
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 1928 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Typed letter signed, as President, The White House, Washington, to Earle P. Charlton regarding the Clarke School for the Deaf.
    - Hoover, Herbert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Autograph manuscript signed, on "Herbert Hoover" letterhead, regarding the "ever growing appreciation of Abraham Lincoln's character and of his immortal service....".
  - "Autographs of the Signers of the Declaration of Independence"
    The volume does not contain autographs of all the signers. Engraved portraits of the signers are present, even though there may not be accompanying autographed material.
    - Adams, John, facsimile from a painting, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Samuel, 1795 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed as governor of Massachusetts, folio, commissioning James Sprout as a major in the State Militia.
    - Bartlett, Josia, 1773 August 30 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed, folio, an arrest warrant for Reuben Peasley, New Hampshire.
    - Carroll, Charles, 1829 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Autograph letter signed to John H. Latrobe asking for a meeting.
    - Chase, Samuel, 1973 January 23 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Autograph endorsement on a petition signed by Charles Cole to the Governor of Maryland, folio, Baltimore.
    - Clymer, George, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed as supervisor of the Revenue, Philadelphia, certifying that duties have been paid on a shipment of gin.
    - Ellery, William, 1815 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Ship's passport, Newport, Rhode Island.
    - Floyd, William, 1817 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed, identure for sale of land in Onedia County, New York, folio.
    - Franklin, Benjamin, 1787 June 9 (Box 4)
      General note
      Item was removed from the album for preservation treatment and rehoused separately.
      Document signed on vellum with seal, oblong folio. Proprietary deed of land to Thomas Gilpin, issued by the Supreme Executive Council of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.
    - Gerry, Eldridge, 1811 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed as Governor of Massachusetts with seal, folio, appointing Jonathan Wild as Justice of the Peace.
    - Hall, Lyman, 1787 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Autograph note signed, seeking a favor.
    - Hancock, John, 1783 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed as Governor of Massachusetts, with seal, folio, summoning newly elected State Senator Benjamin Goodhue to a convention of senators.
    - Harrison, Benjamin, 1783 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      .Document signed by Harrison and Thomas Meriwether, Council Chamber, certifying that "James Cooley is entitled to the proportion of land allowed a Private of the Continental line for three years of service".
    - Hart John, 1776 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Colonial currency. "Three Shillings," signed by Hart and others, Burlington, New Jersey. Printed by Isaac Collins.
    - Heyward, Thomas, 1788 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Warrant for arrest of John Stevenson, signed, Charleston, South Carolina.
    - Hopkinson, Francis, 1780 November 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      United States bank note, signed by Hopkinson as Treasurer of Loans.
    - Huntington, Samuel, 1789 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Autograph letter signed, Norwich, Connecticut, to Enoch Perkins commissioning him as Notary Public in the Court of Hartford.
    - Jefferson, Thomas, 1822 June 27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Autograph letter signed, in the third person, Monticello, expressing thanks to Mr. Samuel Benjamin Helbert Judah for the poem of "Odsfreide" ("Odofriede: the Outcast").
    - Livingston, Philip, 1756 October 6 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Power of Attorney, signed by John Chambers, New York, and witnessed by Livingston and John Ernest, folio.
    - Morris, Robert, 1788 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Autograph letter signed, with integral address leaf, Richmond, to Mathew Ridley in Baltimore relating to business of mutual interest.
    - Paine, Robert Treat, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Fragment of document with good signature. The body of the document is in another hand..
    - Rodney, Caesar, 1774 July 23 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Receipt, signed, for monies paid in discharge of a mortgage, Dover, [Delaware].
    - Rush, Benjamin, 1786 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document, partly printed, signed, no location, swearing that a certificate in the amount of forty dollars is the property of Dickinson College.
    - Sherman, Roger, 1757 March 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Summons, partly printed, signed as Justice of the Peace, Woodbury, Connecticut, for a judgement for debt.
    - Thornton, Matthew, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Signature, clipped.
    - Williams, William, 1794 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Document signed, Lebanon, Connecticut, power of attorney.
    - Wilson, James, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Signature, clipped from letter.
  - "A Collection of American Historical Autographs"
    - Washington, George, 1779 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Letter signed, folio, Head Quarters, Middle Brook, [New Jersey]. to Thomas Burke, delegate to the Continental Congress, relating to the sending of troops to the southern states.
    - Jefferson, Thomas, 1813 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter signed, Monticello, to Lancelot Minor, concerning the sale of land and the matter of book sent for his personal library.
    - La Fayette, Marquis de, 1778 March 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter signed concerning the Canada expedition and Colonel Conway.
    - Hancock, John, 1783 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter signed, Boston, to Governor George Clinton of New York introducing Captain Turner of Boston who is relocating to New York to establish a fencing and dancing school.
    - Clay, H., 1839 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter signed, Ashland [Kentucky], to J. R. Witherspoon declining an invitation to visit Blount Springs, Alabama, as his visit would be "...attributed to an electioneering purpose".
    - Calhoun, J.C., 1814 August 30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter signed to J. R. Witherspoon re appointment of John Brinridge (?).
    - Hobart, John H., 1793 December 17 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Autograph letter signed to John R. Witherspoon reminiscing about college days at Princeton.
    - Johnson, R. (Rinaldo), 1777 February 26 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Signature on Continental currency note of two dollars.
    - Pershing, John and Bishop Charles Henry Brent, Circa 1917 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Signed photograph.